Annibale Ippolito

Senior Software Engineer

Last update: September, 2023

Up-to-date version of CV is available at

https://annippolito.github.io/cv

Residence	♠ <u>Acquappesa, Italy</u>
Linkedin	in <u>annibale-ippolito</u>
Github	nnippolito annippolito
Email	■ <u>annibaleippolito@gmail.com</u>
Phone	+39 3921672716

I'm a Software Engineer with more than 11 years of experience in web development. During my career I developed both frontend than backend skills and in the last years I'm working mostly as a backend. My actual stack is Rest/gRPC - Java/kotlin - Springboot - PostgresqI - GCP and a bit of GO. I'm interested in building and delivering products at large scale. I'm a really motivated person and I like learning, exploring new contexts and trying out new things.

Professional Experience

May 2022 - Present

Alpian

Senior Software Engineer (backend)

As a Senior Software Engineer I'm giving my contribute to:

- Developing new features on the ISP Fideuram CRM system.
- Developing a procedure management service for Legal entities.
- Developing an integration service to ISP Fideuram services.
- Developing a monitoring service to send Customer onboarding events to a postgres database.

This is my first experience in some new technologies such as the Google cloud, gRPC calls and Protocol Buffers.



Nov 2020 - May 2022

Altran Italia Spa

Advanced Consultant (Senior Backend Developer at Expedia Group)

As a Senior Backend Developer consultant at Expedia Group I was building a new brand site in collaboration with Unesco for the sustainable tourism. With my team we provided a form to be used by hotel owners to subscribe their own business and to have a certification released for sustainability.

In that occasion I had the opportunity to play a lot with AWS components.



Nov 2018 - Nov 2020

Expedia Group - Hotels.com

Backend Developer

Worked as Backend developer in a small agile team for the Customer Retention.

- Developed a greenfield microservice to manage the Customers newsletter.
- Developed new feature on a Coupon tool used to generate and validate customer booking coupons.
- Maintain the Customer Profile page.
- Monitor applications with Dropwizard, Graphite, Grafana tools.

• Migrate some other services on the AWS cloud.

It was my first experience in doing Continuous Integration and also in delivering an AWS cloud.

Java Springboot AWS Graphite Grafana Splunk Docker Kubernetes

Dec 2017 - Nov 2018

BNL - Banca Nazionale del Lavoro

Application Architect

I had the chance to work at BNL and support several teams in design applications and guide developers on how to use technologies in banking projects. This experience was really good to me to have hands on design architecture in a team of architects.

Architecture Design SOA Java Soap Websphere Spring Oracle

Apr 2016 - Nov 2017

Capgemini Spa

Software Engineer Lead

I worked on a couple of core business projects in BNL as consultant and I had the opportunity also to Lead a small team of 3. Also I collaborated on the development on the frontend and the backend.

Projects developed:

- Scadenziere: it is a Calendar where users logged in can put a reminder for their deadlines and upload documents with an expiration date. The expiration date is used after to send a reminder.
- Credit biz: it is a Web application where users can ask for a loan from the bank.



Jul 2014 - Apr 2016

JDK srl

Software Engineer

I was working for a small consultant company but I had the opportunity to work as a third parties consultant in several areas.

- GOLDBET BOS (Betting on Smartphone): I contributed to the development of the betting app for goldbet.it. It is a web application downloadable by the google play store or apple store. The core of the frontend was written in angularjs and the backend (not provided by my team) was exposing Rest api.
- SPID: It is a web portal to manage digital identities for legal entities and individuals in Italy. I developed two modules of the web portal: one was dedicated to the registration steps for new users and the second module was dedicated to manage and verify the identities saved by the backoffice.
- AdamVAS: It was a project to manage users in the Wind intranet. I worked as full stack developer using angularjs on the frontend and Spring MVC on the backend.
- BNL IT (www.bnl.it): I worked for the first time as agile developer in a Scrum team. For the most of the project my contribution was on the frontend.



Newtech srl

Software Engineer

It was my first professional experience, where I started with a stage and finalised with a consultant role on Windchill PDMLink.

So I was involved in analysis and development around this PDM. Most of activities were focused on Installations and Customizations on Windchill PDMLink.



Education

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science @ UNICAL

Courses and Certifications

Java Microservices with gRPC | Kotlin for Java developers | Software Architecture Patterns | Apache Kafka | AWS Serverless | Docker for Developers | Amazon Web Services for Developers | Microservices Foundations | Angularis | Object-Oriented Design | Test Driven Design